

JAVIER MORALES

SECURITY ENGINEER

CONTACT

+34633433201

MORALESJMORENO@GMAIL.COM

LINKEDIN.COM/IN/JAVIERMORALESM/
GITHUB.COM/JAVITO-GC

PROFILE

Creative and solutions-driven IT professional with over 12 years of experience in information security, compliance, risk management, and vulnerability assessment. Developing, executing and tracking the performance of security measures to protect information and network infrastructure.

EXPERIENCE

CYBER SECURITY ENGINEER

THE WORKSHOP. (SPAIN) | APR 2022 - PRESENT

- Implementing and managing security systems across the entire organisation's network, including next-generation firewalls (NGFW) intrusion detection/prevention systems (IDS/IPS), web application firewalls, endpoint security solutions, etc.
- System maintenance, troubleshooting and BAU activities for network and endpoint security solutions (SIEM, Network and Application Firewalls, Endpoint Detection Response, Vulnerabilities patching, Access Control & IAM, Cisco Security Suit ESA, SMA and Umbrella).

PLATORM LINUX ENGINEER

THE WORKSHOP. (SPAIN) | MAY 2021 - MARCH 2022

- Administering the organization server infrastructure in a multi-location environment based on Linux/Windows systems running under OpenStack / VMware
- Continuous Integration and Deployment SCM tools (Git, Bitbucket), DNS Automated deployment and maintenance
- Automatization Platform management tools, such as Puppet and Ansible (AWX) to build fas,t automated deployment processes (laaC)

SENIOR SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR & CLOUD ENGINEER

ESENTIRE LTD. (IRELAND) | NOV 2018 - APRIL 2021 CYBERSECURITY MANAGE DETECTION RESPONSE (EDR) 500 - 1000 EMPLOYEES

- Creating and utilizing tools to monitor our applications and services in the cloud including system health indicators, trend identification, and anomaly detection (NOC)
- Planning, designing and developing cloud-based applications and services (IaaS, PaaS, SaaS)
- Developed experience with Cloud-based hosting solutions (AWS-EC2/S3, VMware, VRops)
- Provide High-Level system management solutions

SENIOR TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER

VMWARE (IRELAND) | SEP 2016 - NOV 2018

- Manage and support vSphere and Vrops incidents, multiplatform technical assistance, Network L2/L3 and Storage troubleshooting
- Proactively guide best practices

IT SYSTEMS & OPS ENGINEER

HAVAS MEDIA (SPAIN) | MAY 2015 - AUG 2016

- Managing cloud environments following companies' security guidelines.
- VMware Administrator (P2V Migration deploy, configure and manage virtual infrastructure)
- Hands-on experience on Amazon Web Services AWS (S3, EC2, VPC, CloudWatch)

VMWARE ENGINEER

WINCOR NIXDORF (SPAIN) | MAY 2014 - MAY 2015

- Stealthily plan and lead the deployment of the cloud solution
- VMware SME Subject Matter expert
- Designing and implementing new Virtual Environments (server-less integrated VMware)



JAVIER MORALES

SECURITY ENGINEER

2ND LINE IT ENGINEER

ROCHE PHARMACEUTICAL (SPAIN) | NOV 2013 - MAY 2014

- Strategize daily monitoring, management, troubleshooting and issue resolution to systems and services hosted on cloud resources
- Supporting VMware, Networking, and Backup management, Storage Systems, Blade Servers, SAN, Backup infrastructure

HELPDESK LEVEL 1-2 IT ENGINEER

VODAFONE (SPAIN) | DEC 2010 - NOV 2013

- Advance application support for internal company employees
- Using ticketing tools such as Spider, Remedy and HP Service Manager

EDUCATION

MASTER DIPLOMA IN CYBER SECURITY (MSC LEVEL 9) UNIVERSIDAD DE LA RIOJA UNIR, SPAIN 2020-2021

HIGHER DIPLOMA WITH HONORS IN CLOUD COMPUTER SCIENCE NATIONAL COLLEGE OF IRELAND, IRELAND | 2017-2019

TECHNICAL HIGHER DIPLOMA IN MULTIPLATFORM APPS DEVELOPMENT

I.E.S. I.E.S EL RINCÓN, SPAIN | 2011-2013

TECHNICAL HIGHER DIPLOMA IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS AND INFORMATION SYSTEMS

I.E.S. POLITÉCNICO, SPAIN | 2003-2005

SKILLS

- Software Define DataCenter SDDC
- English & Sapnish
- Amazon AWS (IAM, EC2, S3, CloudWatch, VPC)
- Technical Documentation
- CI/CD Secure Software Dev Life Cycle (SDDLC)
- Security Compliance, ISO 27001, SIEM and SCCM tools
- Veeam Backup & Disaster Recovery
- Linux, DBs, Networking
- VMware Design, Deployment and Implementation
- Monitoring (Nagios, Solarwinds, Service Now)
- Migration Projects (On-Premise to Cloud)
- Python and Bash Automation scripting

CERTIFICATIONS

- VCP550 VCP5-DCV
- DOUBLE VCP VCP6-DCV & VCP6-NV (2V0-621D - 2V0-642 NSX)
- 3V0-623 VCAP 6 DCV DEPLOYMENT
- PMP BY IPMA

- COMPTIA LINUX+
- LPIC-1: SYSTEM ADMININSTRATOR
- AWS SOLUTION ARCHITECT ASSOCIATED
- INTERNAL AUDITOR ISO 27001:2013 BY TÜV RHEINLAND